okay Daniel we're in the atrium on the
Adam doesn't Lewis Center at Oberlin
College and to my right to your left is
the south side of the building meet the
behind you is east side of the building
so the building is a passive solar
design the it sound you hear behind you
is a water sculpture of 600 gallons of
water that flow over a waterfall when
the sun is shining powered by
photovoltaic array outside here going on
your left side attracts the Sun the
atrium is designed as the core of the
building this is the area where we have
public events dinners net the kind of
thing at funerals weddings and variety
kinds of things students when working on
the design of the building block of
space influx from a bit like a town
square
the the Lewis Center is a green building
that's effectively the first Platinum
rated building
not actual platinum graded done
interests college campus three features
about the both green to stand out in a
major way
one is the origins of the design the
building came through a process of
thirteen public design charrette some
public planning meetings specifically
opening doors
said if you want to be part of the
planning process come on in and so we
had about 250 students and faculty and
talents people and anybody who's
interested in building design committed
the process that occurred about 1995 or
the fall 99th live into the spring of
1996 so the way the building began was
as an educational adventure the second
thing that makes it unique I think is
that the standard that emerged in those
public design leads was that we were
trying in this building to cause no
ugliness human or ecological somewhere
else or at some later time if that's a
design standard that gets you thinking
upstream of the building the wells wives
force
and manufacturing places where materials
start to the crystallized into the built
environment but didn't get you thinking
to downstream everything that happens
because of the building so climate
change and species loss and toxification
of the world
those things become a haven as well so
the building has those two features
built into it and then there's a third
thing that's important about the
building there was designed to be not
just a place for education happened but
placed it by the way it was designed
built operated and evolve where the time
became education so the building is
effectively along with the landscape
around it is the laboratory and problems
of sustainability so this years of water
purification and purify the wastewater
on-site is drinking water in drinking
water out the building is a passive
solar design was active photovoltaic
systems that provide about a hundred and
thirty percent of the power demands of
the building so this building exports
power back on the grid
oh hi Rosa net metering states we buy
and sell from the local utility grid
we are also generating more electricity
over the course of a full year that you
use in the building the materials in the
building are certified sources we read a
lot of
safety data sheets to be which are was
are tend to take out toxics as well as
to purchase materials that we certify in
his non hazardous or in case of wood
materials of course that were certified
for long-term sustainable management in
terms of the precise features of the
building I'll walk you around on the
right hand side here out on the south
side this is a placid vein or one
building John Wilde has often been one
of the dwarf all sustainable design the
party in general design for sustainable
development John died in July I think I
needed the plaza behind me this may
happen John
enrichment is work on this building
their news in the middle of this a
annulment or a flagpole looking object
the shadow which falls on my Creed
markers that indicate the seasons of the
year
so the solstices and equinoxes are are
marked
also the spot behind me is finding
seasons to my right now on the east side
of the building beyond the water filter
is a wetland that is a very small
replica ecology of this place clients
this is part of the Great Swamp
stressful
all the way down the south shortly
Destroy mission so if this is a swampy
area did
to take the east side of building and
redevelop that as
sir
as plants in this place before European
so on the back of the hill on the
to my right
well there's
design
engage the material and landscape
since beyond that of the parking lot
above my head
far2 photovoltaic arrays generated
around 160 kW
here that's enough power miss going to
give us welcome to 30 percent surplus
before the
there's a rating slam or hot water that
comes through the slap
[Music]
with 24 Wells out beyond the west side
of the building the canal about 200 name
would be word above my head here
this is certified for sale all the words
in the building warm water over this way
this
she was going to be redesigned by
jean-claude
but standard for the billing is breaking
water in drinking water out this
walking standing in another living
machine designed by Ajanta the second
left materialists his system designed
90 so it's an older system technology is
now better than this process is all the
waste from sinks the toilets of the
building and we recycle
forcing towards
so this is a continuous cycle the water
quality
through this system is good enough to
that EPA in our context
allows us to mix this water plant
this system water right up here
committed now to use
the physical apparatus here is for tanks
that are 7 feet deep you see it at the
top four feet here the water is bubbling
here you can tell
as
solids in suspension to try to maximize
me
and service water call
but this Saxon human race turned into
plant
we process a very small amount of waste
in this field and actually we have no
laughing reason there's nothing to
and there has been some talk
serega
on the east side of this structure
in which case we've made the first
academic department ever in since
Plato's Academy to seek out shit instead
of simply to give it and that would be a
landmark of sorts but this system is
working extremely well and I had a
better problem you'll notice is located
right beside the auditorium so if there
was an issue with
and assistance offering for six years
there imagine this on a larger scale
processing waste from st. boxer
our buildings so drinking water in
drinking water out that's a standard
it's impossible
Daniel this is a 100-seat auditorium
again all the materials here are
certified this is a compressed wheat
straw panel for acoustical buffering
you're standing on a carpet made by
interface carpet in Atlanta Georgia ray
Anderson's company
ray is pioneered the use of carpet as a
product of service so that it goes to a
customer doesn't go to landfill it goes
back to the manufacturer to be
disassembled and reassembled into carpet
the fabric and the seats this is a
fabric made by a company called design
tex we've done a inspired company in new
york this is a compostable fabric and
otherwise your october is very
comfortable but it operates as a kind of
showcase for green design and green
materials the roof becky here the
ceiling decking that's also certified
wood this comes from forest managed for
long-term sustainability in northern
pennsylvania which is about a hundred
miles distant from us
theory the language
it actually originated with project
media markets wanna thank you
monitoring the performance of the
building and the output of the solar
system that he was building powering the
electrical system the building here has
150 data centers that rock band
it's applied no facility so the building
the performance can be made a number of
things to be done now several things
happen in students what is with feedback
from the way the building works and
waited and behave and the goals and that
feedback does design improve bullying
behavior secondly to know exactly how
the building works of building
management much better than applying
turns
conditions that third a it's a way to
educate the public how buildings that
build environment influence everything
beyond how is the building actually
connected to climate to weather into the
electrical grid and so so it's way done
frog legs where the duplicate we didn't
see how systems work but how those
connections operate while this course
students attempted a different second
floor of Lewis building water sculpture
over my left shoulder design is going to
an align at this very event ability know
a bit more head to students by quite
sound and so forth before in here is
also a part of service interface and
this is called raised Lord there's any
it's gap between the bottom of the four
panels and the body of national sub pool
which is where all airflow systems
operated all
a plumbing system so if you need to
change anything that's going you don't
have to tear out anything you take out
the panel too
the screws and your value in the cell
for a bit about the cost of sparkly the
the building the total building cost
total where does be called the project
cost when we build about 7.3 million it
may have been less than that but that's
the number that we got from the college
the actual construction cost is about
1.8 billion that includes also the power
plant and billing protocol randomly
bumping in the 1/2 here wastewater
treatment system and so that includes
things aren't typically a part of
utilities
so the the apples-to-apples comparison
for this particular structure is it
comes in
and the average construction the
buildings of this size built during the
the bidded market in 1998-99 and our
college classroom locks buildings so the
question comes back there a kid your
drill high-performance buildings at or
near or even in some cases full of the
cost of conventional construction on the
answer is yes you can we now have a
large database the experience of
disability is that not only does it save
you long-term costs not only reducing
our health impacts but it also can be
done cost competitive you made these
great buildings Irv Dale it wonderful
places enough in whiskey to learn work
but the real payoff with this building
for me as a teacher is the disk building
and the landscaping around it they've
given us an income for laboratory to
study with the problems of
sustainability kind of auditioners of my
students the rising generation will have
to solve very quickly enforcement 21st
century how do to purify water how do
you avoid change
planet what store or disadvantage how do
you design res ecologic systems in mind
and grow through on-site disability
becomes dental laboratory so it's more
than simply replacing with we hold
classes this building has been wireless
prevented the best laboratory in the
United States on a college campus for
the study of sustainability and a scale
big enough to get to be significant but
small enough to get your mind around the
proper candidate the scale we can not
understand so this as West Jackson has
put it this is Kitty Hawk with ten feet
off the ground the experiment
sustainability continues but the
avengers' Lewis Center is in conjunction
of this whole field psychological design
how we make the human presence on the
planet in a way that is sustainable and
fair decent and just totally new and the
whole educational environment this is a
crossroads for lots of different kinds
of things this is a tracking no
affordable tag array that powers the
water sculpture in the atrium so if the
sun is shining or there's enough
diffused light it will power the pump
but you can hear go higher and lower as
the rate of sunshine rises and falls
behind me here is a pond that is
connected to the wetland around the side
of the building so from a high spot on
the north side of the building
water just gravity feeds into the pond
we capture roof water runoff store that
in a 10,000 gallon storage tank and that
is used to top off the pond and
a year right behind you is a pole the
shadow which can cause on markers here
maybe you want to get the the markers
the great concrete this is the equinoxes
of the year the shadow comes down this
line that's and equinoxes
that's the winter solstice the shortest
day of the year coming up the light is
too faint right now we'll just walk
around here this is a since we are a
classy outfit you may want to focus on
that pink flamingo out here
really was native to this place before
European settlement so the idea here was
to build
this area we take out invasive species
but otherwise leave it pretty much to
the way it evolves so this is a replica
of a wetland about 10,000 years ago the
plants that we reused it here actually
is my meat is part of the orchards for
the building landscape attend to your
right are gardens that are all student
maintain but the goal here was to create
a place that she's a working landscape
it's part of the overall landscape
design and then the photovoltaic array
this is a 100 kW array that's roughly
enough to power say 20 or 25 homes or
sign of the structure
below me right here is a 10,000 gallon
storage tank we try to capture as much
of roof water runoff as we can and
that's used to top off the the wetland
which is straight ahead we just passed
on the east side of the building so try
to save water on-site slow the rate at
which water runs off the site and use
the building as a laboratory in every
way for ecological design and that's